#### **SUJAN NEPALI**

Panauti, Kavrepalanchok, Bagmati, Nepal

Contact No.: +977 9861291592 Email: nepsujan17@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sujan-nepali-b45729123/

\_\_\_\_\_

#### **Profile**

A meticulous GIS and Remote Sensing Analyst, adept in database management, with a solid foundation of more than 6 years in utilizing geospatial-related software for GIS and remote sensing analysis. A year of prior experience as a geospatial full-time consultant and continuing another special service agreement as a geospatial analyst in ICIMOD. Additionally, I had a vibrant and inspiring role as a Geomatics instructor in GIS, Remote Sensing, Cartography, and Surveying, boasting over 4 years of imparting knowledge.

# **Work Experience**

July 2024 - Present Geospatial Analyst, SSA

ICIMOD (International Center for Integrated Mountain Development),

Khumaltar, Lalitpur, Nepal

Working for the preparation of the PURE platform for Bhutan, A solution-

based platform for lift irrigation potential analysis in Bhutan

July 2023 – July 2024 Geospatial Consultant (Full time)

ICIMOD (International Center for Integrated Mountain Development),

Khumaltar, Lalitpur, Nepal

Working for the preparation of the PURE platform for Nepal, A solution-based

platform for lift irrigation potential analysis in Nepal

Aug 2018 - Sept 2022 Geomatics Instructor

Nepal Banepa Polytechnic Institute, Banepa, Kavrepalanchok, Nepal

Courses: GIS, Remote Sensing, Surveying (theory + field)

Nov 2017 - Dec 2017 Engineer Initiate Geomatics

NEA Engineering Company Ltd, Maitighar, Kathmandu, Nepal

Project: "Study and Analysis of Optimal Distributed Generation for Access to Grid Electricity for All in five years with the participation of Local-level

University: Kathmandu University

Government"

GIS mapping and field visit

Aug 2017 GIS Field Researcher

HERD International, Kathmandu, Nepal

Project: "Survey for Urban Equity"

Open street mapping and field surveying using the ODK questionnaire

#### **Education**

### **Master of Engineering in Geoinformatics**

Year passed: June 2024 CGPA: 3.91

Major Subjects: GIS, Remote Sensing, Digital Image Processing, Machine Learning, Deep Learning in Remote Sensing, Scientific Geo-Computing, Spatial data infrastructure & open GIS

Thesis: "Mapping winter crops using high-resolution satellite images and machine learning algorithms."

# **Bachelor of Engineering in Geomatics Engineering**

Year passed: October 2017 CGPA: 3.56

University: Kathmandu University

Major Subjects: GIS, Remote Sensing, Surveying, Photogrammetry, Geodesy, Spatial Database Management System, Spatial Data Infrastructure, Python

Final year project: "Land cover and fragmentation prediction of Chitwan National Park using remote sensing."

# **Paper Publications**

Published papers

Pant, P., Thapa, N., Nepali, S., Sanjel, S. (2024). Land Cover Change Before and After the Sendai Framework of Disaster Risk Reduction.

### **Data Publications**

Bajimaya, D., Bade, B., Nepali, S., Schulthess, U., Sherpa R, S., Blasch, G., . . . Ajay, A. In-situ crop type data for the Terai region of Nepal for 2022-2023 winter season. CIMMYT Research Data & Software Repository Network.

### **Conference Presentations**

Presented on "Trend analysis of agro-meteorological parameters collected using IoT-based ground sensors."

AGSE 2021, Online-Conference, Kathmandu University, Nepal / Stuttgart University of Applied Sciences, Germany

### **Academic projects**

- Building footprint extraction using machine learning approaches like SVM and MLP and comparing their results.
- Soil loss rate estimation using the RUSLE model of Panauti municipality.
- Project on "A Virtual 3D-model construction of an archaeological site using UAV and PiX4D software.

#### **Training**

Oct 25-Nov 4, 2018: Training on "Instructional Skills (IS-2): Classroom Focused." TITI, CTEVT, Sanothimi, Bhaktapur, Nepal

Sep 6-Sep 8, 2016: Training on "Use of UAV for Agriculture and Building Damage Assessment" Kathmandu University, Dhulikhel, Nepal

### Skills

- Survey skills: Proficient in Total station, DGPS, UAV, Kobo Toolbox
- Software skills: GIS (ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, ArcGIS online), Office packages, ENVI, ERDAS Imagine, PIX4D
- Programming skills: Python, Google Earth Engine, R, Matlab
- Other skills include good communication, management, leadership, and field management.

#### Awards and achievements

- Awarded with UGC Formula Funding Scholarship for master's program, 56% at Kathmandu University
- Awarded a government scholarship for a Bachelor in Geomatics Engineering, 33% at Kathmandu University

### **Participations**

- Trainer on "A GIS training on Basic Map Skill and Topographic Mapping" organized by Free Student Union (FSU), Lamjung Campus, held from 21st to 24th May 2018.
- Trainer on 'Training for Developing Basic Map Skills on Disaster Management and Preparedness' held in Jiri, Dolakha, on 23rd–29th October 2016.
- Trainer in the Map Literacy Program conducted in collaboration with the Geomatics Engineering Society (GES) and Surveyor's Society of Kavre (SSK) in different schools of Kavre District (21st to 29th November 2016).

# Memberships

- Member of Nepal Engineering Council, as Geomatics Engineer of category A, 196
- Member of Geomatics Engineering Society (2013 2017)
- Academic and Research Coordinator of GES (2016 session for a year)

### **English Proficiency**

Overall: 6.5

Listening: 7 Reading: 6.5 Speaking: 6.5 Writing: 6

### References

Associate. Professor Reshma Shrestha, PhD

HOD, Department of Geomatics Engineering, Kathmandu University

Email: reshma@ku.edu.np Contact: 977 9841295224

Assistant Professor Uma Shankar Panday

Department of Geomatics Engineering, Kathmandu University

Email: <u>uspanday@ku.edu.np</u> Contact: 977 9851187374

I would like to thank you for taking the time to look at my curriculum vitae. I do solemnly affirm that the information contained here is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.